SaiRam

3575, Owasso Street, #203 Shoreview, Minnesota 55126

Summary

Senior IT Business Analyst / Configuration Analyst / Functional Consultant with 10+ years' experience in JD Edwards, SAP CRM in the Sales & Distribution / Inventory / Transportation / CRM functional areas with top Manufacturing / Retail /Distribution companies. Skilled in ERP project life cycle development from inception through implementation and support with a consistent track record of meeting deadlines and objectives. My goal is to innovate/ design / implement best practices and utilize effective OCM compliant technologies to provide exceptional Customer service/ Logistics performance.

- JD Edwards(World, XE, 8.0/9.1) , SAP ECC 6.0 (Sales & Distribution)
- SAP CRM 7.0
- Kewill Transportation Management system.
- Upgrade / Implementation / Migration / Production support
- Data Access Studio, SQL Developer.
- Software Development Life cycle
- System Testing / Impact and Performance Analysis
- Functional / Technical Specifications / Design / Review
- Change Management
- Problem Management/ Production support
- Strong written / verbal communication skills
- SOX Compliance / FDA Regulatory processes

Work Experience

POST Foods, INC. Saint Louis, Missouri

Jan 2014 - Till date

Cell: 612-437-2653

E-mail: vallmur11@yahoo.com

IT Business Analyst (Upgrade) – JD Edwards One World/E1 8.0/9.1, MS SQLServer, LENS (Liaison), DAS Reporting. TMS, EDI, Advanced Pricing, SO/PO Mgmt.,

- Implemented the migration of 'Transportation Management System' replacing NLI with CFM a third party logistics /TMS provider.
- Well versed with the base configuration related to Transactions/Master data of Transportation management system.
- Possess very good understanding/expertise of various attributes of JDE-TMS routes/rate schedules such as 'Performance rating'/Transit/Lead days and their impact on JDE determination/sales transactions.
- Developed an IT process to upload the Transportation routes/Rates in view of implementing new TMS and hence new set of preferred carriers
- Have a very good understanding / resolved several time sensitive issues related to logistics related EDI Transactions / Routing options in conjunction with JDE shipment confirmation.
- Effectively streamlined the way Base Pricing/Advanced pricing (G/L Accruals, off invoice, Bracket pricing,Free Goods, Promotions) after inheriting from Ralcorp and currently being used at POST.
- Created Blue print (future use) for maintaining a determination rule to determine the 'Adjustment Schedule' that gets associated to the sales order (in place of being an attribute of the customer master).
- Have a very good understanding of critical attributes of Advanced Pricing module such as Adjustment code other adjustment definitions.
- Demonstrated to the Leadership team the way SAP handles advanced pricing system(Pricing Procedure) compared to the way JDE handles the same (Adjustment schedule).
- Configured / implemented/Supported the Sales Order management/ Purchase order management/Inventory management.
- Well versed with the EDI JDE configuration related to the transaction sets 850(Inbound PO), 940 (EDI WMS/TMS messages), 214 (Shipment details from the TMS/WMS), 945 (EDI shipment confirmation that functions in conjunction with JDE shipment confirmation process.

- Also worked on other EDI transactions 855(PO Acknowledgement), 856(ASN) 810 (EDI Invoice).
- Designed/tested/ implemented the customization to trigger 940 transaction from the standard sales order entry application.
- Extensively worked /trouble shoot the EDI Transaction set messages on the Liaison system (LENS that interfaces/Map between Customer/TMS/WMS and JDE Application.
- Provided very critical reports related to JDE Master/Transaction data to PwC as part of SOX/FDA Audit/Compliance.
- Worked closely/coordinated with the IBM IT team as a liaison between IT and the business user community.
- Created several complex reports for the management using Data Access Studio, SQL Developer.

STRYKER, INC. Kalamazoo, Michigan

Sep 2012 – Dec 2013

IT Business Analyst (Change Control/Upgrade)(– JD Edwards One World /9.0, AS400, IBM iSeries.

- Key member of the MDET project team. The initiative is, in addition to the Federal Tax Laws compliance; optimize the tax liability by realizing the tax saving opportunities.
- Requirements gathering, Authoring Functional specifications/design, work closely with the development team in converting the Functional design to Technical design.
- Authoring Test scripts, Executing/ Recording test results/ validation.
- Work several Change requirements through the Change control process using 'Master Control'.
- Responsible in the identification of the Inventory areas in an initiative to leverage Tax saving opportunities.
- Identified several attributes of the Item master & the same that was used in conjunction with several Transaction types to determine the categories that are not liable for taxes.
- As a part of FDA regulatory compliance, devised a mechanism to load the FDA code / MDL (Medical Device Listing) to the JDE Supplier Item Cross reference file and also established a process for the Regulatory business team to maintain FDA/MDL codes.
- Designed/Developed/Tested/Implemented "Product Data Acquisition "tool from ERP for eCAPA project (Corrective and Preventive Action).
- Involved in changes to the Vertex Integration components for functionality with the SP24 upgrade.
- Provided resolution to several time sensitive production issues/ reporting requests.

BESTBUY, INC. Minneapolis, Minnesota

Mar 2009 – Aug 2012

IT Data Analyst – CRM – JD Edwards OW Xe, Sales Force.

- Primarily responsible for the Data Acquisition & building model related to enterprise customer (B2B & B2C) that was used for Customer Analysis (CAM Customer Analytics Master).
- Data acquisition from several external lists like InfoUSA, EQUIFAX, Epsilon.
- Coordinated the integration initiative between Data warehouse and IBM Netezza (Landing zone CAM)
- As part of the strategic team responsible for coordination between various teams (owners of various data sources)
- Acted as liaison between the delivery team and the leadership / Executive Sponsor team.

Cargill, INC, Minneapolis, Minnesota (Wipro)

Jan 2008 – Mar 2009

Lead – Technical Development – CRM – JD Edwards OW Xe, E1 8.0 SAP CRM 6.0, SAP ECC (S&D) 6.0

- Part of the Management team in formation of the development organization.
- Well versed with the Procure to Pay / Inventory modules/ processes.
- Well versed with the ST/OT cycle in JD Edwards
- Coordination of the development effort from the technology center overseas.
- Designing the schema, managing the different aspects of SDLC including project planning, Estimations and Resource management.
- Study and document the key Business processes and provide the functional inputs to the development team.
- Initiating quality processes and review methods.

- Business requirements, Functional specification/design, Test strategy and maintain the repository to record the test results/data.
- Report of several performance metrics to Wipro/Cargill management.
- Traceability matrix, Deviation management.

Medtronic, INC, Minneapolis, Minnesota (IBM).

Oct 2002 - Dec 2007

IT Business Analyst (Implementation / Migration – CRM – JD Edwards, IBM iSeries, AS400, SAP CRM 6.0, SAP ECC (S&D) 6.0.

- Key member of the 'Data Conversion team' during the migration from JD Edwards to SAP ECC 6.0 & SAP CRM 7.0, by performing the GAP analysis of key Business processes and Data sources.
- Designed / Configured the Copy control functionality (Transaction types/Item categories) to implement the home grown business process / Functionality Bill & Replace (Field Inventory/Consignment transfer).
- Designed/ Configured Pricing procedures/ Access Sequences / Condition types-tables to implement the Advanced Pricing functionality that handles 'Upcharges'.
- Designed / Configured the Organization data functionality in streamlining various divisions and effectively utilized the concept of 'Container elements' during determination of Sales commissions for Field Reps.
- Designed / Configured the 'Organization Data profile' in simulating the DCM (Distribution Control Matrix) as part of FDA regulatory requirement.
- Performed the Gap analysis between the attributes of Customer Master (JDE) and Business Partner (SAP), Designed/ Configured the 'Partner Determination Procedure' attribute of the Business Partner.
- Effectively utilized the 'Item category' functionality of the Transaction types in determining the Transactions that are liable for Medical devices taxes.
- Designed / Led the development effort in implementing the 'Manifest' Project—Kewill Transportation system with ERP Logistics execution /Shipment confirmation process for all the US Distribution centers.
- Actively participated System Validation / Internal Audit processes as part of SOX/FDA Compliance.

YPW Associates. Atlanta, Georgia.

Developer – JD Edwards World, One World Xe, AS400.

Jul 2001 - Sep 2002

- Involved in the Soft code changes for Program P42520 for the special projects Carrier Consolidation, Sales Rep Consolidation, and Ware House Location Consolidation.
- Involved in changes to the Shipment confirmation program P4205 to accommodate the line splitting at the time of Shipment confirmation program.
- Testing the enhancements/ Changes, Documenting the results.

Non- ERP Experiences

Aug 1991 – Jun 2001

ITI (Indian Telephone Industries), Albedo Systems Inc., AceTech. Bangalore, India.

Programming in C, C++, Borland C++.

- Involved in the Application Development Projects related to 'Data Acquisition Systems' from several Analog sources for Defense Establishments in India.
- Involved in the development of the Project 'Prediction and Analysis of Execution Time'.
- Actively involved in Preparation/ Readiness for several clients involving ISO certification / TQM (Total Quality Management) and BPR (Business Process Reengineering).

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical & Electronics) University Of Mysore. 1991.